In this video, we will be talking about
the
junction rule and Kirchhoff's current law.
So what is Kirchhoff's current law?
Well, Kirchhoff's current law states that
the
total current passing through a junction
is
equal to zero. What does that mean?
Well, first I'll write the formula. Let's
say
we have a junction like this.
And the current going over here gets
distributed here. Let's call this I1, I2,
and
I3. Well, I1 plus I2 plus I3
equals zero. Now, the thing is that you
might
be wondering is that means that some of
these
values have to be negative for them to be
zero,
or they have to be zero, which they
probably
aren't. How does that work?
Well, whether it's negative or positive,
that
doesn't mean the current itself is
negative
or positive. That just means the
direction.
The sign indicates the direction.
When there's a current going towards a
junction,
something like this, the sign would be
positive.
If it's going away, it's negative.
Let's have an example over here. Let's say
we
have a junction over here, and there is a
current
I1 with a current of 5 amps.
And I2 will have a current of negative 3
amps.
So we want to find I3.
Well, since the sum of all the currents is
equal
to zero, we know that I1 plus I2 plus I3
is equal to zero. So, negative 3, since
it's
negative, it means that the current is
going
away. This current is going towards, and
we
need to find this. So, I3 plus 5 plus 3
equals
zero. Sorry, minus 3 equals zero, because
that's
negative 3. Minus 3 equals zero.
So, I3 would be equal to negative 2.
Since I3 is equal to negative 2, that
means
that the current will be going away.
However,
in some cases, when I3 or whatever you're
calculating
is positive, then the current would be
going
towards the junction. It would look
something
like this. Let's say I1 is 5 again, and
however, I2 this time is negative 7 amps.
So we need to calculate I3.
First of all, let's look at the direction.
Since
this is negative, this will be going away
from
the junction, and this would be going
towards,
since it's positive. 5 minus 7 plus I3
equals
zero. So, in that case, then I3 is
positive
2, equals positive 2.
What this means is that since it's
positive,
it would be going towards the junction.
So,
the current would be going somewhere like
this.
These two go towards here, which gets
outputted
into I2. So, it really depends on the sign
to
see and know the direction of the current.
Let's have a harder example.
Let's say we have a 5-way junction.
It goes here, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
And what we're given is 3 of
the values over here. So, I5, let's try to
calculate
I5 and I3. And what we're given is I3
equals
2I5.
And I2 would be, let's say, negative 8
amps.
I1 equals 6 amps.
And I4 is equal to negative 25 amps.
First of all, let's illustrate and try to
depict
what is going to happen over here. Since
I1
is positive, it's going to be going
towards
the junction. Well, these two negative
ones
will be going away from the junction. Now,
let's
use Kirchhoff's Law. The sum of the
currents
is equal to zero. So, I1 plus I2
plus I3 plus I4 plus I5 is
equal to zero. We can substitute this into
our
equation. Just convert this into 2 times
I5,
2I5. And we could also plug in all our
other
values. So, 6 minus 8 plus 2I5 plus
negative 25 plus I5 equals
to zero. So, when you combine this, you
get
3I5 plus negative 8 minus 25 plus 6 would
be
equal to negative 27. Negative 27 plus 3I5
equals
zero. So, what we'll get is we will get
3I5
equals 27. So, I5 will ultimately be equal
to
9. I5 equals 9.
And since I5 equals 9 and we know I3
equals
2I5, I3 equals 2I5, then I3 would
be equal to 2 times 9, which is equal to
amps and 9 amps.
So, since these are positive, that means
that
they are going to be going towards the
junction.
So, what we can get from this is we used
Kirchhoff's
law and some algebra from what we're given
to
calculate the current and direction of two
of
the junction segments. And this is really
useful
in a lot of circuit problems and it's
pretty
relatively easy to remember. Just remember
that
the sum of all the currents is equal to
zero
in a junction. Remember also that positive
current
means it's going towards the junction,
while
negative means it's going away. But
positive
and negative don't actually mean that the
magnitude
is positive or negative. It just
symbolizes
and depicts a direction. Thank you for
listening
and I hope you learned something from this
video.
Bye!